Dynamic Programming solves problems efficiently by
remembering past results.
Consider calculating 1 + 1 + 1 + 1 + 1.
A computer might calculate this step-by-step.
Without memoization, each time it needs a sum, like 1+1, it
recalculates it from scratch.
Memoization stores results of expensive calls, returning cached
results for the same inputs.
For 1+1+1+1+1, after 1+1=2, it remembers '2'.
When 2+1 is needed, it uses the stored '2'.
This trades a little memory to store results for a significant boost
in processing speed.
This fundamental concept, trading memory for speed, is the essence of
Dynamic Programming.
Understanding memoization optimizes algorithms, a crucial skill for
any developer or student.