Electromagnetism is a fundamental force.
Faraday's Law of Induction explains how changing magnetic fields
create electric currents.
Consider a simple setup: a wire coil connected to a
meter and a bar magnet.
Stationary, the meter shows no current.
But move the magnet near or through the coil, and the meter registers
current with 'energy ripples' around the coil.
This is electromagnetic induction, core of Faraday's Law: changing
magnetic flux through a circuit induces
electromotive force, or voltage.
Not just a curiosity, it's the principle behind modern technologies
like wireless charging for devices.
In wireless charging, the pad's transmitting coil creates a
fluctuating magnetic field, inducing current in the
device's receiving coil.
This energy transfer, thanks to Faraday's Law, powers devices without
physical connections, simplifying lives and advancing technology.
From power generation to gadgets, Faraday's Law shapes our
technologically advanced world, enabling innovation.